Research assistants can produce polished answers while hiding how
they searched, what they actually read, and which decisions
belonged to the researcher. RAGdoll was built to keep
those receipts.
This is the real RAGdoll terminal, resuming a documented
acceptance investigation about video generation models. The recorded run
was completed locally with Ollama and Qwen three, four
B. No OpenAI API call is simulated in this
recording.
RAGdoll turns an ambiguous question into a structured research
brief and an executable search plan. The researcher can
inspect every axis, query family, inclusion rule, and source
before approving discovery. Search never starts silently.
Approved queries run through scholarly source adapters. Results are
deduplicated and ranked with visible score components and reasons.
This run retrieved twenty four candidates, but the human
selected the six papers that entered the evidence workflow.
Paper selection and evidence acquisition are separate approvals. RAGdoll
records the source, retrieval state, evidence level, and page
count. Five papers supplied open full text and one
used an explicitly labeled abstract fallback.
The resulting dossier contains seven checkpointed sections and twenty
five cited claims. It states its evidence boundary instead
of claiming exhaustive coverage or novelty. Every accepted citation
identifier had to be present in the bounded evidence
supplied for that section.
A citation is not decorative. From any claim, the
researcher can inspect the exact indexed passage, paper identifier,
page locator, and evidence level. Unsupported questions fail closed
instead of inviting the model to guess.
Model output crosses Pydantic validation before entering domain logic,
while narrow adapters own retrieval, storage, and permissions. Codex
accelerated repository analysis, implementation, testing, and security review. RAGdoll
also contains a real Responses API adapter configured for
GPT five point six. It is contract tested, not
presented as live in this capture.
The acceptance run indexed three hundred seven page-aware chunks.
A manual passage audit found twenty three of twenty
five claims directly supported, preserving the two failures as
evidence that citation integrity is not automatic entailment. RAGdoll
helps researchers move faster without giving up judgment, provenance,
or the ability to check the receipts.